Guide to the William L. Mertz transportation collection, 1955-1990
George Mason University Libraries
- William L. Mertz transportation collection
  - Stars AC Propulsion Project 8/85 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    A technical report by Westinghouse Electric Corporation for Department of Transportation about an electric propulsion system for passenger rail service.
  - Trolleybus Propulsion Evaluation 8/87 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    A report by Booz, Allen and Hamilton evaluating 4 different propulsion systems used in San Francisco Municipal Railway system.
  - Inverter-Controlled ac Induction Motor Propulsion System, Volume 1 Executive Summary 3/89 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Inverter-Controlled ac Induction Motor Propulsion System, Volume 2: Final Report 3/89 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Research, Development and Design of a Steerable Transit Truck 3/90 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    prepared for Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority [truck is used in the science of railroad usage]
  - Dulles Airport Access Road Corridor Transit Alternatives Study 6/90 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Battery Energy Storage for Rail Transit Systems 4/96 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    by Carnegie Mellon for DOT
  - Barney Circle Freeway Modification Project: Environmental Assessment 8/95 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Research and Technology Development in Advanced Road Transport Telematics 1993 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    produced by Commission of the European Communities
  - Uniform State Regulations: Report to Congress post 1/82 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    report required by Motor Carrier Act of 1980
  - Development of Track Maintenance Training and Maintenance Management Information System Programs 7/92 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    report completed for Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority
  - STARS [Subsystems Technology Application to Rail Systems] - - Improved Air Comfort System Volume 1 and 2 11/83 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Includes a study of 5 commuter rail systems, Bay Area Rapid Transit District (BART), Port Authority Transit Corp (PATCO), Chicago Transit Authority (CTA), Port Authority Trans-Hudson Corp (PATH) and Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA)
  - Cold Weather Transit Technology Program; Characteristics of Ice and Snow at the Interface with Transit Vehicle Surfaces 9/81 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Michi Roads In Japan 1995 8/7/95 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    bi-lingual
  - Telecommunications Network Modernization and the New Jersey Economy 12/91 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Advanced Group Rapid Transit [AGRT] Program Review 3/83 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - National Highway Study: Congressional Hearings Part 1 and 2 1953 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Extract from Congressional Hearings 1953 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - A Factual Discussion of Motor truck Operation, Regulation, and Taxation 1951 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    A Reprint of a statement made by Thomas H. MacDonald, Commissioner of Public Roads, to a Senate subcommittee in 6/50
  - The Local Rural Road Problem 1/50 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    a report to Congress on rural roads
  - Highway Needs of the National Defense 6/30/49 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    Message from the President of the United States to Congress
  - A Study of Highway Costs and Motor Vehicle Payments in the United States 1/30/39 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    Association of American Railroads
  - Engineering Works: The Sanitary District of Chicago 8/23 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Maryland Transportation: A Historic Focus 9/1976 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Highway Statistics Summary to 1975: Motor Fuel 6/77 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - American Road Builder 1969 5/1969 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    articles on the Highway Trust Fund, Utility relocation, Peace Corp Road Project
  - War Worker Transportation 1943 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Citizen Participation and Housing Development 1974 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Intelligent Vehicle Highway Systems 1/1992 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Economic and Social Effects of Highway Improvements 1961 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    part of a joint research program between Michigan State University, Michigan State Police and the Bureau of Public Roads
  - Highway Taxes and Fees: How they are Collected and Distributed 1984 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    Fed'l Highway Administration pamphlet
  - 1972 Census of Transportation 10/73 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Symposium on Challenges and Opportunities for Global Transportation in the 21st Century 10/26/95 - 10/27/95 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    symposium presentation papers from several of the participants
  - Instructional Manual for preparation of the 1979 Estimate of the Cost of Completing the Interstate System 1/23/78 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Rail Car Cost Containment Study 8/88 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Highway Statistics 1982 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Power Rate Structure Aspects of Energy Cost for Rapid Transit Systems 6/82 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Management of Urban Construction Programs: Volumes 1 and 2 1980 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Will it Promote Economic Growth? 7/18/62 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - National Conference on Suburban Mobility 11/30/89 - 12/1/89 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    Summary of conference results, findings and presentations. Prepared by GMU national Center for Suburban Mobility
  - Three Case Studies: The Impact of Deferred Maintenance in Rail Transit 7/85 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Subway Tunnel Energy Study 7/88 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    Explored the feasibility of using subway tunnel air as a heat sink/heat source for surrounding buildings.
  - Saving Energy in U.S. Transportation (Box 59, Folder 12)
    Office of Technology Assessment, Congress of the United States
  - Intelligent Vehicle-Highway System (IVHS) Projects in the U.S. 1/92 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - AGS [Automated Guideway Systems] Socio-Economic Research Program Digest 3/83 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Videotape Cassette, 5 1/4" Diskettes 1980s (Box 60)
    VHS of Road to Happiness (1924) and updated introduction from 1980s. Diskettes contain U.S. highway information from the 1960s.